RG 062:159, Town of Wethersfield
Connecticut State Library
Town of Wethersfield records
1723-1981
Connecticut State Library
Wethersfield (Conn.)
53 cubic feet
Administrative, election, court, military, school, tax and vital records for the town of Wethersfield.
RG062_159
T000630
Historical Note
The town of Wethersfield was settled in 1634, named in 1637 and incorporated in May 1832.
Scope and Content
Administrative, election, court, military, school, tax and vital records for the town of Wethersfield.
Index Terms
Alternate Creators:
Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (Wethersfield)
Subjects:
Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield; Elections -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield -- Statistics; Voting -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield -- Statistics; Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield; Deeds -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield -- Registers; Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield; Writs -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield; Slaves -- Connecticut -- Wethersfield
Places:
Wethersfield (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Wethersfield (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1723-1981
  - Calendared records, including town officers, boundaries, meeting house records, land transactions, taxes, highways and bridges, slaves, indentures, care of the poor and legal records, 1723-1821 (Box Boxes 1-5)
  - Town meeting records, including warnings for meetings and resolutions, 1815, 1915-1916 (Box Box 6)
  - Lists of voters, electors and freemen, 1798-1891 (Box Box 6)
  - Voters at town meetings, 1837-1840 (Box Box 6)
  - Election returns, 1802-1838 (Box Box 6)
  - Selectmen's reports, 1852-1867 (Box Box 6)
  - Records of appointment or election of town officers, 1784-1874 (Box Box 6)
    unprocesed
  - Indentures, 1779-1851 (Box Box 7)
  - Appointments of overseers, 1761-1881 (Box Box 7)
  - Records relating to naming jurors and licensing taverns and retailers, 1823-1838 (Box Box 7)
  - Records relating to roads, highways, ferries and bridges, 1822-1867 (Box Box 7)
  - Records of military service, including enlistments, bounty receipts and surgeon's reports, 1862-1898 (Box Box 7)
  - Deeds, 1807-1913 (Box Box 7)
  - Records relating to care of the poor, including correspondence, bills and accounts, and records about administration of Hospitality Lodge, 1762-1829 (Box Box 8)
  - Records relating to care of the poor, 1762-1829 (Box Box 9)
  - Probate and estate papers, including the estates of Bulkley, Latimer and Woodhouse, 1838-1907 (Box Box 9)
  - Abstracts of births, marriages and deaths, 1854-1891 (Box Box 9)
  - Records relating to boundaries, church property, deposit fund, petitions for new towns, bonds, physician licenses, circa 1820-1902 (Box Box 10)
  - First School Society Treasurer's book, includes lists of burial plot owners, 1863-1909 (Box Box 10)
  - School accounts, 1813-1891 (Box Box 10)
  - Tax abstracts
    - 1730-1749 (Box Box 11)
    - 1750-1773 (Box Box 12)
    - 1774-1789 (Box Box 13)
    - 1790-1799 (Box Box 14)
    - 1800-1809 (Box Box 14a)
    - 1810-1818 (Box Box 14b)
  - Assessor's books
    - 1824-1828 (Box Box 14c)
    - 1828-1833 (Box Box 14d)
    - 1833-1838 (Box Box 15)
    - 1839-1843 (Box Box 16)
    - 1824-1828 (Box Box 17)
    - 1848, 1861-1864 (Box Box 18)
    - Third school district, 1849 (Box Box 18)
    - Newington society, 1829, 1833-1842 (Box Box 19)
    - Newington, 1843-1847, 1849, 1853, 1863 (Box Box 20)
    - Rocky Hill, 1835-1836 (Box Box 20)
  - Rate books
    - 1826, 1835-1836, 1887-1909 (Box Box 21)
    - 1910-1922 (Box Box 22)
    - 1925-1927 (Box Box 23)
    - Fire district, 1911, 1915-1916, 1918-1919, 1921-1929 (Box Box 24)
    - Wolcott Hill fire district, 1918-1928, 1931 (Box Box 25)
  - First Ecclesiastical Society taxes, 1842 (Box Box 26)
  - Personal tax, 1915-1919 (Box Box 26)
  - Town tax, 1923-1924, 1928 (Box Box 26)
  - Rate books for First School Society and Second, Third and Fourth School Districts, 1804, 1837-1841, 1892-1909 (Box Box 27)
  - Tax abatements, 1807-1858 (Box Box 27)
  - Individual tax lists, 1800-1805 (Box Box 27)
  - Grand lists, 1800-1804 (Box Box 28)
  - Register of tax liens, 1897-1907 (Box Box 28)
  - Assorted tax records, 1785-1845 (Box Box 28)
  - Writs of attachment, 1811-circa 1850 (Box Box 28)
  - Writs of attachment, circa 1850-1922 (Box Box 29)
  - Justice of the Peace records, 1744-circa 1890 (Box Boxes 30-41)
  - Justice of the Peace records, circa 1890-1900 (Box Box 42)
  - Pound and dog registers, 1808-1907 (Box Box 42)
  - Selectmen's account books, 1814-1856 (Box Box 43)
  - Ledger, 1829-1855 (Box Box 43)
  - Town treasurer's reports, 1815-1883 (Box Box 44)
  - Bills, receipts and orders for payment, undated (Box Box 44)
  - Bills, receipts and orders for payment, 1780-1913; includes 2 record cartons (Box Boxes 45-48)
  - Town Clerk's correspondence, 1855-1876 (Box Box 49)
  - Historic District Commission minutes and administrative files, 1971-1981 (Box Boxes 50-52)
  - Tax abstracts, 1850 (Box Box 53)
  - Individual tax lists, 1846-1921; 89 volumes
    These volumes are not boxed.
    Volumes have varying titles on their covers such as: list, asssessment list, tax levys, assessment book, assessors book, grand list or no title at all.
    Years 1847, 1850, 1863 are missing.
    Years 1851-1852, 1854-1860, 1865-1869 have 2 volumes for each year.
    There are 3 volumes for 1920: A-K, L-Z, non-residents. There is only one volume for 1921: non-residents.
  - Real estate property abstracts, 1956-1958; 3 volumes